这是阿斯加德难民船领袖号
This is the Asgardian refugee vessel Statesman.
我们受到了攻击
We are under assault.
重复 我们受到了攻击
I repeat, we are under assault.
漫威电影宇宙10周年
引擎受损 生命保障系统失灵
The engines are dead, life support failing.
请求范围内任何船只的救援
Requesting aid from any vessel within range.
这段求救录音是雷神1的导演配音的
我们目前位于距阿斯加德22跳跃点的位置
We are 22 jump points out of Asgard.
我们的船员都是阿斯加德平民
Our crew is made up of Asgardian families.
我们的士兵寥寥无几
We have very few soldiers here.
这不是战舰
This is not a warcraft.
重复 这不是战舰
I repeat, this is not a warcraft.
听我说 你们该感到欣喜
Hear me and rejoice.
伟大的泰坦拯救了你们 这是无上的光荣
You have had the privilege of being saved by the Great Titan.
也许你们认为这是灾难
You may think this is suffering.
不
No.
这是救赎
It is salvation.
宇宙万物的天平 因为你们的牺牲而走向平衡
Universal scales tip toward balance because of your sacrifice.
微笑吧
Smile.
即使是死亡
For even in death,
你们也成为了灭霸的孩子
you have become Children of Thanos.
我知道失败是什么滋味
I know what it's like to lose.
明明知道自己是正义的
To feel so desperately that you're right...
却还是无力回天
yet to fail, nonetheless.
当恐惧
It's frightening.
使你两腿发软
Turns the legs to jelly.
我问你什么是最后的结局
But I ask you, to what end?
害怕或是逃避
Dread it, run from it...
命运终会到来
destiny arrives all the same.
就在现在 就在这里
And now, it's here.
或者我应该说
Or should I say...
我就是命运
I am.
你话太多了
You talk too much.
要宇宙魔方
The Tesseract.
还是你哥哥的脑袋
Or your brother's head.
我想你应该知道该怎么做
I assume you have a preference.
当然
Oh, I do.
杀了他吧
Kill away.
够了 停下！
All right, stop!
宇宙魔方没在我们手上
We don't have the Tesseract.
它与阿斯加德一起毁灭了
It was destroyed on Asgard.
我怎么会有你这样的弟弟
You really are the worst brother.
我向你保证 哥哥
I assure you, brother...
我们会没事的
the sun will shine on us again.
你的乐观用错了地方 阿斯加德人
Your optimism is misplaced, Asgardian.
好吧 第一 我不是阿斯加德人
Well, for one thing, I'm not Asgardian.
其次...
And for another...
我们有浩克
we have a Hulk.
让他也活动活动
Let him have his fun.
众英烈
Allfathers...
让暗魔法再次流过我的身体
let the dark magic flow through me one last...
最后一次
time.
你不该这么做
That was a mistake.
不！
No!
你一定会为此偿命的
You're going to die for that.
卑微的我
My humble personage...
向您的伟大臣服
bows before your grandeur.
从来没有人 有如此强大
No other being has ever had the might...
如此尊贵
nay, the nobility...
能够支配不仅一枚 而是两枚无限宝石
to wield not one, but two Infinity Stones.
整个宇宙都在您的掌握之中
The universe lies within your grasp.
还有两枚宝石在地球上
There are two more stones on Earth.
找到它们 我的孩子们 把它们给我带回泰坦星
Find them, my children, and bring them to me on Titan.
我们不会让您失望的 父亲
Father, we will not fail you.
请让我插句话
If I might interject.
如果你们要去地球 最好带上一个向导
If you're going to Earth, you might want a guide.
对于那里 我可以说是很有经验的
I do have a bit of experience in that arena.
你说的是你那些失败的经验吧
If you consider failure experience.
我认为是经验中的经验
I consider experience experience.
全能的灭霸
Almighty Thanos...
我 洛基 阿斯加德的王子
I, Loki, prince of Asgard...
奥丁之子
Odinson...
约顿海姆的正统国王
the rightful king of Jotunheim...
诡计之神
god of mischief...
在此向你投诚
do hereby pledge to you...
不死的忠诚
my undying fidelity.
不死？
Undying?
你用词应该更小心一点
You should choose your words more carefully.
你...
You...
永远不会成为...
will never be...
一个真正的神
a god.
不
No!
这次不会复活了
No resurrections this time.
不 洛基
No. Loki.
不是开玩笑吧？ 你一分钱都没有？
Seriously, you don't have any money?
对物质的需求会背离对精神的追求
Attachment to the material is detachment from the spiritual.
那我跟熟食店的伙计说说
I'll tell the guys at the deli.
也许他们能给你做个精神火腿面包
Maybe they'll make you a metaphysical ham on rye.
等等 我觉得我有200
Oh. Wait, wait, wait. I think I have 200.
美元？
Dollars?
- 卢布 - 也就是？
- Rupees. - Which is?
1.5美元吧
Uh, buck and a half.
你想吃点什么
What do you want?
给我点个金枪鱼三明治就行
I wouldn't say no to a tuna melt.
灭霸要来了
Thanos is coming.
他要来了...
He's coming.
谁？
Who?
慢点儿 慢点儿 我来说说清楚
Slow down, slow down. I'll spell it out for you.
你在说胡话呢
You're totally rambling.
- 我没有 - 我没听懂
- No, I'm not. - You lost me.
你知道那种 在梦里 想上厕所的感觉吧
Look, you know how you're having a dream,and in the dream you gotta pee.
当然
- Yeah. - Okay.
好 然后你就会发现 哦不
And then you're like, "Oh, my God.
这儿没卫生间 我该怎么办？
"There's no bathrooms. What am I gonna do?
- 哦！ 有人在看！ - 对
- "Oh, someone's watching." - Right.
噢 我要尿在裤子里了 - 然后你就醒了
"Oh, I'm gonna go in my pants." - And then you wake up and in real life
然后你真的想上厕所
you actually have to pee.
- 没错 - 对吧
- Yes. - Yeah.
每个人都有过
- Okay. - Everybody has that.
对了 这就是我想表达的
Right, that's the point I'm trying to make.
昨天晚上 我梦见 我们有了一个孩子
Apropos of that, last night I dreamt we had a kid.
特别真实
It was so real.
还用你那个古怪叔叔的名字给他取了个名
We named him after your eccentric uncle.
他叫什么来着？
Uh, what was his name?
- 摩根 - 对
- Right. - Morgan! Morgan.
- 所以你醒来 - 是的
- So you woke up... - Naturally.
认为我们...
...and thought that we were...
- 要有了 - 对
- Expecting. - Yeah.
- 有吗？ - 没有
- Yes? - No.
我都梦到了 那么真实
I had a dream about it. It was so real.
如果你真的想要一个孩子
If you wanted to have a kid...
你就不要一直戴着它
you wouldn't have done that.
我很高兴你提到这事 因为这没什么
I'm glad you brought this up, 'cause it's nothing.
只是个纳米单元的容器而已
It's just a housing unit for nanoparticles.
这借口也太糟了
You're not helping your case, okay?
这是可以拆下来的 并不是...
No, this is detachable. It's not a...
你不需要它
You don't need that.
我知道 我动过手术了
I know, I had the surgery.
我只是想保护我们
I'm just trying to protect us...
我们的未来 仅此而已
and future usses and that's it.
万一衣柜里有个怪物呢
Just in case there's a monster in the closet.
- 而不是 你明白我的意思 - 衬衫
- Instead of, you know... - Shirts.
你太了解我了
You know me so well.
都知道我想说什么
- God. - You finish all my sentences.
你的衣柜里应该有衬衫
You should have shirts in your closet.
是的
Yeah.
其实你知道那里面应该有什么吗？平静的生活
You know what there should be? No more surprises.
我们今晚要好好吃一顿
We're gonna have a nice dinner tonight.
炫耀一下这枚海瑞温斯顿(美国高端奢侈珠宝品牌)的钻戒
Show off this Harry Winston.
不会再有别的事打扰我们了 再也不会了
Right? And we should have no more surprises. Ever.
我向你保证
I should promise you.
- 好啊  - 我保证
- Yes. - I will.
谢谢你
Thank you.
托尼·斯塔克
Tony Stark.
我是史蒂芬·斯特兰奇博士 我需要你跟我来
I'm Doctor Stephen Strange. I need you to come with me.
对了 恭喜你们结婚
Oh, uh, congratulations on the wedding, by the way.
抱歉  你是发什么演出门票的吗?
I'm sorry, you giving out tickets to something?
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
毫不夸张地说
It's not overselling it to say that
这关系到整个宇宙的命运
the fate of the universe is at stake.
“我们”是指谁？
And who's "we"?
嗨 托尼
Hey, Tony.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
- 小辣椒 - 嗨
- Pepper. - Hi.
你还好吗?
- Oh. - You okay?
宇宙之初
At the dawn of the universe,
只是一片虚无 然后
there was nothing. Then...
砰！
Boom.
宇宙大爆炸带来了六种元素宝石
The Big Bang sent six elemental crystals...
在原始的宇宙中飘荡
hurtling across the virgin universe.
每颗无限宝石
These Infinity Stones
都控制着一种宇宙本源属性
each control an essential aspect of existence.
空间
Space.
现实
Reality.
力量
Power.
灵魂
Soul.
心灵
Mind.
还有时间
And Time.
再跟我说一遍他的名字
Tell me his name again.
灭霸
Thanos.
他是一场灾难 托尼
He's a plague, Tony.
他侵略其他星球 予取予求
He invades planets. He takes what he wants.
他屠杀半数的生灵
He wipes out half the population.
是他派出了洛基
He sent Loki.
纽约的那场袭击 幕后就是他
The attack on New York, that's him.
就是这个
This is it.
我们还有多少时间？
What's our timeline?
不知道 他已经得到了力量和空间宝石
No telling. He has the Power and Space Stones.
这就已经能让他成为 宇宙最强了
That already makes him the strongest creature in the whole universe.
如果他拿到全部的六颗宝石 托尼
If he gets his hands on all six stones, Tony...
他就能以前所未有的方式屠杀生命
He could destroy life on a scale hitherto undreamt of.
你刚才是说“前所未有”吗？
Did you seriously just say "hitherto undreamt of"?
万物之鼎：漫画中奇异博士用来观测世界的道具
你现在是倚在“万物之鼎”上吗？
Are you seriously leaning on the Cauldron of the Cosmos?
就是这东西吗？
Is that what it is?
我不跟一个斗篷计较
I'm going to allow that.
如果灭霸要集齐六颗宝石
If Thanos needs all six, why don't we just
我们为什么不把这一颗毁掉？
stick this one down a garbage disposal?
不行
No can do.
我们发过誓要用生命保护时间宝石
We swore an oath to protect the Time Stone with our lives.
我也发过誓再也不吃乳制品
And I swore off dairy...
但Ben&Jerry's(著名冰淇淋品牌)以我命名了一种冰淇淋 所以...
but then Ben & Jerry's named a flavor after me.So...
- 斯塔克狂妄榛子味 - 听起来不错
- Stark Raving Hazelnuts. - Not bad.
听着就不好吃
A bit chalky.
我们最喜欢的是大块浩克热巧克力
A Hunk of Hulk of Burning Fudge is our favorite.
- 真有这个吗？ - 总之
- That's a thing? - Whatever.
重点是 任何事都能改变
Point is, things change.
我们保护时间宝石的誓言不能改变
Our oath to protect the Time Stone cannot change.
这颗宝石也许是我们对抗灭霸最好的机会
And this stone may be the best chance we have against Thanos.
相对而言
Yeah, so conversely,
这也可能是他对付我们的最好工具
it may also be his best chance against us.
除非我们没能尽到职责
Well, if we don't do our jobs.
那你的职责是什么
What is your job exactly?
除了捏气球动物
Besides making balloon animals.
保护你生活的世界 混球
Protecting your reality, douchebag.
好了 各位 能把这个话题先放一放吗？
Okay, guys. Could we table this discussion right now?
目前 这颗宝石在我们手上
The fact is we have this stone.
我们知道它在哪
We know where it is.
幻视戴着心灵宝还不知道在哪
Vision is out there somewhere with the Mind Stone...
我们得马上找到他
and we have to find him now.
问题就在这
Yeah, that's the thing.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
两周前 幻视关掉了他的通讯器
Two weeks ago, Vision turned off his transponder.
他离线了
He's offline.
什么？
- What? - Yeah.
托尼 你又弄丢了一个超级机器人？
Tony, you lost another super-bot?
我没有弄丢 他不是这么简单  他在进化
I didn't lose him. He's more than that. He's evolving.
那谁能找到幻视？
Who could find Vision then?
该死
Shit.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯或许能
Probably Steve Rogers.
- 哦 太好了
Oh, great.
也许吧
Maybe.
但是...
But...
给他打电话啊
Call him.
没那么简单
It's not that easy.
天呐 我们真是好久没联络了
God, we haven't caught up in a spell, have we?
没有
No.
复仇者联盟解散了 结束了
The Avengers broke up. We're toast.
解散 ？
Broke up?
像乐队那样？披头士那样？
Like a band? Like... Like the Beatles?
队长和我闹翻了
Cap and I fell out hard.
已经不再联系了
We're not on speaking terms.
托尼 听我说
Tony, listen to me.
索尔死了
Thor's gone.
灭霸要来了
Thanos is coming.
你跟谁闹翻已经不重要了
It doesn't matter who you're talking to or not.
翻盖手机
Flip phone.
(史蒂夫·罗杰斯)
博士 你不是故意让你的头发在动吧
Say, Doc, you wouldn't happen to be moving your hair, would ya?
至少现在没有
Not at the moment, no.
你没事吧？
You okay?
- 帮他一把 - 班纳
- Help him! - Banner!
- 王 动作快点 - 好的
- Wong! Look alive! - Go, go! We got it!
星期五 发生了什么？
Friday, what am I looking at?
不清楚 我正在调查
Not sure. I'm working on it.
你最好把你那块时间宝石收起来
Hey! You might wanna put that Time Stone in your back pocket, Doc!
还是拿出来用吧
Might wanna use it.
内德 帮我吸引一下注意力
Ned, hey. I need you to cause a distraction.
见鬼！
Holy shit.
我们死定了
We're all gonna die!
那有一艘飞船
There's a spaceship!
- 怎么回事 - 我的天
- What's going on? - Oh, my God!
你们这帮孩子怎么回事？
What's the matter with you kids?
没见过宇宙飞船吗？
You never seen a spaceship before?
星期五 疏散43号街以南的平民
Friday, evac anyone south of 43rd Street.
通知应急部门
Notify first responders.
好的
Will do.
听我说 你们该感到欣喜
Hear me and rejoice.
你们将死于
You are about to die
灭霸大人的儿女之手
at the hands of the Children of Thanos.
要心怀感恩
Be thankful...
你们无意义的生命能贡献于...
that your meaningless lives are now contributing...
对不起 地球今天打烊了
I'm sorry, Earth is closed today.
你们最好收拾东西离开这里
You better pack it up and get outta here.
宝石守护者
Stonekeeper.
这只啰嗦的动物是你的发言人吗？
Does this chattering animal speak for you?
当然不是 我自己会说
Certainly not. I speak for myself.
你们已经擅自闯入地球的领土
You're trespassing in this city and on this planet.
意思是让你们滚蛋 章鱼哥
He means get lost, Squidward.
他真是烦人
He exhausts me.
把宝石拿来
Bring me the stone.
班纳 你也上吗？
Banner, you want a piece?
不 我不太想
Mmm, no, not really.
不过现在也由不得我了
But when do I ever get what I want?
这就对了
That's right.
好久不见了
It's been a while.
有你在就踏实多了
It's gonna be good to have you, buddy.
我只是 我需要集中一下注意力
Let me just... I need to concentrate here for a second.
出来 快出来啊
Come on, come on, man.
那家伙呢？
Where's your guy?
不知道 我们最近有点问题
I don't know. We've sorta been having a thing.
现在不是有问题的时候 那才是问题
- It's no time for a thing. - I know.That's the thing right there. Let's go.
哥们 你让我巫师面前下不来台了
Dude, you're embarrassing me in front of the wizards.
抱歉 托尼 要么是我不能... 要么是他不想...
Tony, I'm sorry. Either I can't or he won't.
没关系
It's okay.
退后吧 帮我看他一下 谢谢 - 交给我吧 - 见鬼
Hey, stand down. Keep an eye on him. Thank you. - I have him. - Damn it.
这玩意哪来的？
Where'd that come from?
-纳米科技 不错吧 我把...
It's nanotech.You like it? A little something I...
班纳博士 既然你那位绿色的朋友不打算现身
Doctor Banner, if the rest of your green friend won't be joining us...
还是赶快把宝石转移走吧
Gotta get that stone outta here, now.
我誓死守护宝石
It stays with me.
那好 再见
Exactly. Bye.
托尼 没事吧 情况如何？
Tony, you okay? How we doing? Good? Bad?
很好 很好 你真的不打算帮忙吗？
Really really good. Really good. Do you plan on helping out?
我尽力了 他就是不肯出来
I'm trying. He won't come out.
小心
Hammer.
快点 浩克 你这是怎么回事
Come on, Hulk! What are you doing to me?
出来 出来 快出来
Come out! Come out! Come out!
不！
No!
你说 不 是什么意思？
What do you mean, "no"?
嘿 斯塔克先生 这是怎么了？
Hey, man. What's up, Mr. Stark?
- 孩子 你怎么在这？ - 艺术博物馆校园考察
- Kid, where'd you come from? - A field trip to MoMA.
斯塔克先生 这家伙什么情况？
Uh, what is this guy's problem, Mr. Stark?
他是从外星来的 想偷走一个巫师的项链
Uh,he's from space.He came here to steal a necklace from a wizard.
你的能力很特别 一定很受孩子的欢迎吧
Your powers are quaint.You must be popular with children.
咒语不难 但没那么容易破解
It's a simple spell but quite unbreakable.
那你就去死吧
Then I'll take it off your corpse.
如果我死了...你就...别想破解咒语
You'll find removing a dead man's spell troublesome.
你只会生不如死的
You'll only wish you were dead.
不！
No!
孩子 就是那个巫师 跟上他 - 好的
Kid, that's the wizard. Get on it. - On it!
这可不好
Not cool.
抓住你了
Gotcha!
等等
Wait!
斯塔克先生 我要被吸走了
Uh, Mr. Stark, I'm being beamed up.
坚持住 孩子
Hang on, kid.
王 你一定要来参加我的婚礼
Wong, you're invited to my wedding.
星期五 给我来点猛的
Give me a little juice, Friday.
解锁17:A
Unlock 17:A.
彼得 你现在放手 我会接住你的
Pete, you gotta let go. I'm gonna catch you.
不是说要救那个巫师吗
But you said save the wizard!
我不能呼吸了！
I can't breathe.
海拔太高了 你会缺氧的
We're too high up. You're running out of air.
原来如此
Yeah. That makes sense.
斯塔克先生 这就像新车的那种味道
Mr. Stark, it smells like a new car in here!
一路顺风 孩子 - 星期五 送他回家 - 好的
Happy trails, kid. - Friday, send him home. - Yep.
不是吧
Oh, come on!
老板 波兹小姐来电
Boss, incoming call from Miss Potts.
托尼 天呐
Tony? Oh, my God.
你还好吗？ 发生了什么？
Are you all right? What's going on?
我没事 不过八点半的晚餐可能要推迟了
Yeah, I'm fine. I just think we might have to push our 8:30 res.
为什么？ - 因为我得晚点才能回去
Why? - Just 'cause I'll probably not make it back for a while.
别告诉我你在那艘船上
Tell me you're not on that ship.
我在
Yeah.
天啊 不 告诉我你不在那艘船上
God, no, please tell me you're not on the ship.
亲爱的 我很抱歉
Honey, I'm sorry.
我很抱歉 我不知道该说什么
I'm sorry, I don't know what to say.
给我回来 托尼 我发誓...
Come back here, Tony. I swear to God.
- 佩珀... - 快给我回来...快回来
- Pep. - Come back here right now.Come back.
老板 信号要断了 我的信号也...
Boss, we're losing her. I'm going too.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
我真该待在校车上的
I shoulda stayed on the bus.
你要去哪？ - 时间宝石被夺走了
Where you going? - The Time Stone's been taken.
圣殿现无人守护 你有何打算？
The Sanctum remains unguarded. What will you do?
我得打个电话
I'm gonna make a call.
(史蒂夫·罗杰斯)
(外太空)
BGM：The Spinners《The Rubberband Man》
唱啊 德拉克斯
Sing it, Drax!
我们为什么要这么做来着？
Why are we doing this again?
那可是个求救信号 火箭 我们不能见死不救
It's a distress signal, Rocket. Someone could be dying.
我知道 但是我们为什么要去？ - 因为我们是好人
I get that, but why are we doing it? - Cause we're nice.
也许他们会给点好处作为报酬呢
And maybe whoever it is will give us a little cheddar cheese for our effort.
- 这不是重点 - 这不是重点...
- Which isn't the point. - Which isn't the point.
如果他们不给报酬的话... - 就把他们飞船开走
I mean, if he doesn't pony up... - We take his ship.
- 说的没错！- 完全正确！- 很棒
- Exactly! - Bingo! - All right!
我们就要到了
We are arriving.
好的 队员们 这趟可能会有危险 大家都凶起来
All right, Guardians,don't forget this might be dangerous...so let's put on our mean faces.
格鲁特玩的是雅达利2600游戏《保卫者》
格鲁特 别玩儿那东西了 快点 我不想说第二遍 格鲁特
Groot, put that thing away, now. I don't wanna tell you again. Groot.
我是格鲁特！
I am Groot!
- 喔！注意语言
- Whoa! - Language!
嘿
- Hey! - Wow.
你是越来越不像话了 小子
You got some acorns on you, kid.
自从你开始分泌树液 就变成了一个混球了
Ever since you got a little sap, you're a total d-hole.
你再玩 我就把那破玩意儿给你砸了
Now, keep it up, and I'm gonna smash that thing to pieces.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我的天
Oh, my God.
看来我们拿不到报酬了
Looks like we're not getting paid.
雨刷 开雨刷 把这玩意弄掉
Wipers! Wipers! Get it off.
这哥们居然还能活着
How the hell is this dude still alive?
他可不是个哥们 你这样的是哥们
He is not a dude. You're a dude.
这是个爷们儿
This... This is a man.
俊朗帅气 肌肉发达的爷们儿 - 我也肌肉发达啊
A handsome, muscular man. - I'm muscular.
开玩笑吗？奎尔 你和胖之间就差个三明治了
But who are you kidding, Quill? - You're one sandwich away from fat.
得了吧 - 是真的 你是胖了 - 什么？
Yeah, right. - It's true, Quill. You have put on weight. - What?
卡魔拉 你也觉得我...
Gamora, do you think I'm...
他很焦虑 愤怒
He is anxious, angry.
他失去了很多 非常内疚
He feels tremendous loss and guilt.
他就像天使和海盗所生的孩子
It's like a pirate had a baby with an angel.
哇哦
Wow.
你们真的点醒我了 好吧
This is a real wake-up call for me. Okay.
我得买套博飞(美国健身品牌) 开始锻炼 先买副哑铃
I'm gonna get a Bowflex. I'm gonna commit. I'm gonna get some dumbbells.
你知道哑铃是不能吃的吧？
You know you can't eat dumbbells, right?
这就像是科塔蒂金属一般的肌肉
It's like his muscles are made of Cotati metal fibers.
别给他做肌肉按摩了
Stop massaging his muscles.
把他弄醒
Wake him up.
醒来吧
Wake.
你们是些什么人？
Who the hell are you guys?
自从我认识灭霸 他就只有一个目标
The entire time I knew Thanos, he only ever had one goal.
通过抹除一半的生命 来维持宇宙的平衡
To bring balance to the universe by wiping out half of all life.
他原来不断的杀戮 屠杀一个又一个的星球
He used to kill people planet by planet,massacre by massacre.
包括我的星球
Including my own.
如果他得到了所有六颗无限宝石
If he gets all six Infinity Stones...
他打一个响指就能达成目的 像这样
he can do it with the snap of his fingers like this.
你似乎对灭霸很了解
You seem to know a great deal about Thanos.
卡魔拉...是灭霸的女儿
Gamora is the daughter of Thanos.
你父亲杀了我弟弟
Your father killed my brother.
冷静
Oh, boy.
是养父 严格来说 她和你一样痛恨灭霸
Stepfather, technically. And she hates him as much as you do.
家家有本难念的经
Families can be tough.
我父亲死之前告诉我 我有一个同父异母的姐姐
Before my father died,he told me that I had a half-sister...
被囚禁在地狱里
that he imprisoned in Hel.
然后她回到了家里 还刺瞎了我的眼睛 不得不杀了她
And then she returned home and stabbed me in the eye. So I had to kill her.
也许这就是命运 总是颠沛流离...我能理解你的痛苦
That's life though, isn't it, I guess. Goes round and round and...I feel your pain.
我也理解你们的痛苦
I feel your pain as well, because...
不是要跟你比什么 但我也经历了不少
I mean, it's not a competition,but I've been through a lot..
我爸杀了我妈
My father killed my mother.
然后我就不得不杀了我爸 这也很艰难
And then I had to kill my father. That was hard.
应该比你杀姐姐更艰难
Probably even harder than having to kill a sister.
毕竟 我双眼还是完好的
Plus, I came out with both my eyes, which was...
我需要一个锤子 而不是汤匙
I need a hammer, not a spoon.
怎样打开这玩意
How do I open this thing? Is there some sort of, uh...
是不是输入什么四位数密码 生日一类的
A four-digit code, maybe? Maybe a birthdate.
- 你在干嘛？- 开走你们的副舱
- Uh, what are you doing? - Taking your pod.
不行
No, you're not.
你不可以借走我们的副舱 先生
You will not be taking our pod today, sir.
奎尔 你在故意压低嗓音说话吗？
Uh... Quill, are you making your voice deeper?
- 我没有 - 你就是
- No. - You are.
你就是在模仿这位男神 很别扭
You're imitating the god-man. It's weird.
我没有 - 他又学了一次
No, I'm not. - He just did it again!
这就是我的声音
This is my voice.
你在嘲讽我吗？
Are you mocking me?
你在嘲讽我吗？ - 你又来了一次
- Are you mocking me? - Stop it. You did it again.
他这是在模仿我
He's trying to copy me.
你最好闭嘴 - 够了 - 是他先开始的
I need you to stop doing that. - Enough! - He's doing it first.
我们得去阻止灭霸
We need to stop Thanos.
也就是说 我们必须找出 他的下一个目的地
Which means we need to find out where he's going next.
虚无知地
Knowhere.
虚无的地方要怎么去
He must be going somewhere.
不不 虚无知地
No, no. Knowhere?
那是个地方 我们以前去过 很糟糕
It's a place. We've been there. It sucks.
- 不好意思 那是我们的食物 - 不再是了
- Excuse me, that's our food. - Not anymore.
索尔 为什么他要去虚无知地
Thor, why would he go to Knowhere?
因为几年来
Because for years...
现实宝石一直安全地由那儿一个叫作收集者的人保管
the Reality Stone's been safely stored there with a man called the Collector.
如果是在收集者手上 那就不叫安全
If it's with the Collector, then it's not safe.
白痴才会把宝石交到那种人手里
Only an idiot would give that man a stone.
- 或者是天才 - 你怎么知道他不会去找其他宝石
- Or a genius. - How do you know...he's not going for one of the other stones?
宇宙中一共有六个宝石
There are six stones out there.
灭霸已经拿到了力量宝石
Thanos already has the Power Stone...
因为上周他血洗了山达尔星
because he stole it last week when he decimated Xandar.
他从我这抢走了空间宝石
He stole the Space Stone from me...
还摧毁了我的飞船 杀害了我半数的子民
when he destroyed my ship and slaughtered half my people.
时间宝石和心灵宝石在地球上很安全 由复仇者们守护
The Time and Mind Stones are safe on Earth. They're with the Avengers.
- 复仇者？ - 地球最强大的英雄
- The Avengers? - Earth's mightiest heroes.
《浑身是劲》主演
就像凯文·贝肯？
Like Kevin Bacon?
也许现在有他吧 我不知道 我很久没去过地球了
He may be on the team. I don't know. I haven't been there in a while.
至于灵魂宝石 从没有人见过 甚至没人知道它在哪
As for the Soul Stone, well, no one's ever seen that. No one even knows where it is.
所以灭霸暂时无法染指
Therefore Thanos can't get it.
因此他会去虚无知地
Therefore he's going to Knowhere.
去拿到现实宝石 不客气
Hence he'll be getting the Reality Stone. You're welcome.
那我们就马上赶去虚无知地
Then we have to go to Knowhere now.
错 我们要去的是尼达维
Wrong. Where we have to go is Nidavellir.
- 这地名是什么人编的吧 - 地名都是人编的
- That's a made-up word. - All words are made up.
真的存在尼达维这个地方吗？
Nidavellir is real? Seriously?
那地方是个传奇
That place is a legend.
那里锻造的神兵利器 足以横行整个宇宙
They make the most powerful, horrific weapons to ever torment the universe.
我还真想去见识一下
I would very much like to go there, please.
这兔子说得不错 你们当中就他最聪明 - 兔子？
The rabbit is correct and clearly the smartest among you. - Rabbit?
只有矮人王伊崔才能打造出我要的武器
Only Eitri the Dwarf can make me the weapon I need.
我猜你一定就是船长了 - 你还真有眼光
I assume you're the captain, sir. - You're very perceptive.
果然是位英明的领袖 愿意和我一同远征尼达维吗
You seem like a noble leader. Will you join me on my quest to Nidavellir?
我得问下船长 等一下 我就是船长
Let me just ask the captain. Oh, wait a second, it's me!
- 走吧 - 很好
- Yeah. I'll go. - Wonderful!
事实上我才是船长 - 闭嘴
Uh, except for that I'm the captain. - Quiet.
- 还有 你拿的是我的背包 - 奎尔 给我坐下
- That's my backpack. - Go sit down.
听着 这是我的飞船 而且我才不去...
Look, this is my ship. And I'm not goin' to...
等下 你刚才说是什么样的武器
Wait, what kinda weapon are we talkin' about here?
能杀了灭霸的武器
The Thanos-killing kind.
这样的武器 我们不应该人手一把吗
Don't you think that we should all have a weapon like that?
不 你们没有足够驾驭武器的力量
No. You simply lack the strength to wield them.
你的意识会崩溃 身体也会支离破碎
Your bodies would crumble as your minds collapsed into madness.
这么诡异 我倒更想去看一看了 - 确实
Is it weird that I wanna do it even more now? - Mmm, a little bit, yeah.
如果我们没去虚无知地 而让灭霸再拿到一颗宝石
If we don't go to Knowhere and Thanos retrieves another stone...
那时候他就无人能敌了
he'll be too powerful to stop.
- 他现在已经是了 - 我想到一个办法
- He already is. - I got it figured out.
我们有两艘飞船 还有一群各式各样的白痴们
We got two ships and a large assortment of morons.
我和格鲁特跟这位男神走
So me and Groot will go with the pirate angel here.
你们这些白痴就去虚无知地阻止灭霸
And the morons will go to Knowhere to try to stop Thanos.
- 怎样 不错吧 - 很不错
- Cool? Cool. - So cool.
说实话
For the record...
我知道你跟他走 是想躲着灭霸
I know that you're going with him because it's where Thanos isn't.
对船长讲话的时候 态度要端正点 奎尔
You know, you really shouldn't talk that way to your captain, Quill.
走吧 格鲁特 把游戏机放下 非得玩傻了
Come on, Groot. Put that game down. You'll rot your brain.
祝你们好运吧 白痴们 再见
I bid you farewell and good luck, morons. Bye.
幻视？
Vis?
又是宝石引起的吗？
Is it the stone again?
它好像在和我说什么
It's as if it's speaking to me.
它说了什么？
What does it say?
我...不知道 一些...
I don't... I don't know, but something.
告诉我 你感觉到了什么
Tell me what you feel.
我只感觉到你
I just feel you.
(苏格兰)
10点钟有趟去格拉斯哥的火车
So there's a 10:00 a.m. to Glasgow...
这样你走之前 我们还能多待一会儿
which would give us more time together before you went back.
要是我错过那班火车呢 - 11点还有一班
What if I miss that train? - There's an 11:00.
要是我错过所有车次呢
What if I missed all the trains?
要是这次 我不回去了呢？
What if this time I didn't go back?
但是你向斯塔克承诺了 - 我更想对你承诺
But you gave Stark your word. - I'd rather give it to you.
也有人在等我回去 我们都向别人做出了承诺
Well, there are people who are expecting me too, you know. We both made promises.
可我们彼此却没有
Not to each other.
旺达
Wanda.
这两年 我们来之不易的相聚 想给我们这段感情一个交代
For two years, we've stolen these moments... trying to see if this could work and...
我不知道 我只是想把自己的想法说出来
I don't know. You know what, I'm just gonna speak for myself.
我觉得... - 我懂 我都懂
I think... - It works. It's work.
留下吧
Stay.
跟我一起
Stay with me.
或者算了 要是我太...
Or not. If I'm overstepping...
(突发新闻 纽约遭袭击)
那是什么？
What are they?
这就是宝石想要警告我的东西
What the stone was warning me about.
(特别报导 托尼·斯塔克失踪)
我得走了
I have to go.
不 幻视 如果那是真的
No, Vision. Vision, if that's true,
或许真的你不该回去
then maybe going isn't the best idea.
旺达 我...
Wanda, I...
幻视！
Vision!
那一刀 让我的身体不听使唤了
The blade, it stopped me from phasing.
- 怎么会这样 - 我也不知道
- Is that even possible? - It isn't supposed to be.
我的系统正在紊乱
My systems are failing.
早知道这样...我们还不如一直待在床上
I'm beginning to think we should have stayed in bed.
幻视！
Vis!
交出宝石 就放她一命
Give up the stone, and she lives.
放开他
Hands off.
快 快
Come on. Come on.
快点 你得站起来 站起来 快
Come on, you gotta get up. You gotta get up. Come on. Hey.
我们要赶紧离开
Hey. We have to go.
你快走 拜托 - 是你要我留下的
Please. Please leave. - You asked me to stay.
我要陪着你
- I'm staying. - Please.
- 快起来 - 我动不了
- Get up. - I can't.
我们可以杀了你们 只是不想这么做
We don't wanna kill you, but we will.
你们再也没有这个机会了
You'll never get the chance again.
能站起来吗？
Can you stand?
谢谢你 队长
Thank you, Captain.
先扶你上飞机吧
Let's get you on the jet.
我记得 我们都说好了
Now, I thought we had a deal.
跟紧队伍 保持联络 绝不轻易冒险
Stay close, check in, don't take any chances.
对不起 我们只是想多聚一会儿
I'm sorry. We just wanted time.
队长 我们去哪儿？
Where to, Cap?
回家
Home.
我们不会有事的
We'll be safe. We'll be safe.
泽侯贝里族人
Zehobereians.
妈妈！我的妈妈在哪
Mother! Where's my mother?
站到两边 否则死路一条 - 妈妈
Choose a side or die. - Mother!
一边 是真理的启示 另一边 是少数人才拥有的荣誉
One side is a revelation...the other an honor known only to a few.
怎么了 小家伙？
What's wrong, little one?
我妈妈 我妈妈在哪儿？
My mother. Where is my mother?
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
卡魔拉
Gamora.
你有成为战士的潜力 卡魔拉
You're quite the fighter, Gamora.
来 让我来帮你
Come. Let me help you.
看
Look.
很漂亮 对不对
Pretty, isn't it?
完美的平衡 万物都该如此
Perfectly balanced, as all things should be.
如果一边倾斜的太多 那另一边就...
Too much to one side or the other...
给 你试试
Here. You try.
安详地离开 去见你们的造物主吧
Now, go in peace to meet your maker.
集中注意力
Concentrate.
看 你已经掌握了
There. You've got it.
卡魔拉
Gamora.
你知道这些手雷是会爆炸的那种 还是只会冒烟的那种
Do you know if these grenades are the blow-off-your-junk kind or the gas kind?
因为我正考虑 往我裤腰带上挂两个
Because I was thinking about hanging a couple on my belt right here.
怕一不留神让我绝后... - 我需要你帮我个忙
But I don't want to if they're the... - I need to ask a favor.
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
不管怎样 我们最终都会与灭霸交手
One way or another, the path that we're on leads to Thanos.
所以我才准备了手榴弹
Which is what the grenades are for.
抱歉 要我帮什么忙
Uh, I'm sorry. What's the favor?
如果不幸
If things go wrong...
我被灭霸抓住了
If Thanos gets me...
我要你向我保证
I want you to promise me...
你会杀了我
you'll kill me.
什么
What?
我知道一件他不知道的事
I know something he doesn't.
如果他发现了
And if he finds it out,
整个宇宙都将陷入危机
the entire universe could be at risk.
你知道什么？
What do you know?
如果我告诉你 你也知道了
If I tell you, you'd know too.
如果它真的那么重要...难道我不该知道吗？
If it's so important... shouldn't I?
除非你想死
Only if you wanna die.
为什么总是知道的太多就会死这种剧情？
Why does somebody always have to die in this scenario?
你就...
Just...
相信我吧 只要可能 就杀了我
Trust me. And possibly kill me.
我是说 我是想 我真的会 但是你...
I mean, I'd like to. I really would. But you...
向我发誓
Swear to me.
以你母亲的名义 向我发誓
Swear to me on your mother.
好
Okay.
老兄 你在那儿站了多久了？
- Oh. - Dude. How long have you been standing there?
一个小时
An hour.
一个小时？
An hour?
不会吧？
Are you serious?
我已经掌握了一种能力
I've mastered the ability
能一动不动地站着
of standing so incredibly still...
以至于没人看得到我 看着
that I become invisible to the eye. Watch.
你在吃扎格果
You're eating a zarg-nut.
我的动作
But my movement...
如此缓慢
was so slow...
无法察觉到 - 并不是
that it's imperceptible. - Mmm, no.
我非常确信我已经隐形了 - 嗨 德拉克斯
I'm sure I'm invisible. - Hi, Drax.
见鬼
Damn it.
(虚无知地)
这地方似乎已经废弃了
This place looks deserted.
第三象限有动静
I'm reading movement in the third quadrant.
是的 我也看到了
Yep, I'm picking that up too.
我们就在这儿降落吧
Let's put down right here.
宝石不在我这
I don't have it.
全宇宙的人都知道
Everyone in the galaxy knows
你连亲兄弟都能卖掉
you'd sell your own brother...
只为了增加一点
if you thought it would add even the slightest trinket...
你那可悲的收藏品
to your pathetic collection.
卡魔拉背后的容器里是导演罗素兄弟早期作品《发展受阻》里托比亚斯博士
片尾字幕可以看到迪士尼为这个彩蛋要了授权
我知道现实宝石在你手上 蒂万
I know you have the Reality Stone, Tivan.
交出来 可以让你免受很多痛苦
Giving it to me will spare you a great deal of suffering.
我说过了 我把它卖了
I told you. I sold it.
- 我为何要说谎呢
Why would I lie?
谎言对你来说就如同呼吸一般自然
I imagine it's like breathing for you.
那岂不是找死
Like suicide.
还算心里有数
You do understand.
难道你为了这东西连性命都不要了
Not even you would surrender something so precious.
我之前不知道那是什么
I didn't know what it was.
那么你比我想象的还要蠢
Then you're more of a fool than I took you for.
就是他 - 最后的机会 你这骗子
It's him. - Last chance, charlatan.
宝石在哪儿？
Where's the stone?
今天
Today...
德拉克斯
Drax. Drax.
我要让他 为我妻女的死付出代价
...he pays for the deaths of my wife and daughter.
德拉克斯 等等
Drax, wait.
还不到时候 德拉克斯
Not yet, not yet, not yet. Drax.
德拉克斯 听我说
Drax, Drax, Drax. Listen to me.
他还没拿到宝石呢
He doesn't have the stone yet.
如果我们拿到宝石 我们就能阻止他
If we get it, then we can stop him.
我们得先拿到宝石 对吧
We have to get the stone first. Yeah.
不
No.
不 为了奥维特 为了卡米莉亚
No. For Ovette, for Camaria.
睡吧
Sleep.
好了 卡魔拉 曼蒂斯 你们走右边
Okay. Gamora, Mantis, you go right.
是另一个右边
The other right.
为什么？
Why?
为什么是你？ 女儿
Why you, daughter?
这就结束了
That was quick.
无与伦比 无与伦比 无与伦比
Magnificent! Magnificent! Magnificent!
我感到的是你的悲伤吗 女儿？
Is that sadness I sense in you, daughter?
我知道你还是在乎我的
In my heart, I knew you still cared.
但也说不准
But one never knows for sure.
现实总是令人失望
Reality is often disappointing.
但已成为过去
That is, it was.
现在开始
Now...
现实可以任我掌控
reality can be whatever I want.
你早知道我会来 - 早就等着了
You knew I'd come. - I counted on it.
我们需要好好地谈谈 孩子
There's something we need to discuss, little one.
灭霸！
Thanos!
不
No!
Grimace：麦当劳九十年代吉祥物，浑身紫色
放开她 紫薯精 - 彼得
Let her go, Grimace. - Peter.
我说了叫你走右边
I told you to go right.
现在还争这个？ - 快放开她
Now? Really? - You let her go!
哦 小男朋友- 不
Ah, the boyfriend. - No.
我觉得我更像 长期专杀泰坦的赏金猎人
Like to think of myself more as a Titan-killing, long-term booty call.
- 放开她 - 彼得
- Let her go. - Peter.
不然 我打烂你下巴上那个阴囊
I'm gonna blow that nutsack of a chin right off your face.
不是他
Not him.
你保证过的
You promised. You promised.
女儿 你对他的期望过高了
Oh, daughter. You expect too much from him.
是她要求你的 对吧？
She's asked, hasn't she?
开枪啊
Do it.
开枪
Do it!
说了叫你走右边的
I told you to go right.
我爱你 胜过一切
I love you more than anything.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我欣赏他
I like him.
还是没有幻视的消息吗
Still no word from Vision?
卫星显示他最后一次出现在爱丁堡
Satellites lost him somewhere over Edinburgh.
编剧Stephen McFeely客串了国防部长旁边的秘书
在失窃的昆式战斗机上 和四名全球头号通缉犯在一起
On a stolen Quinjet with four of the world's most wanted criminals.
是您非要选择用“通缉犯”称呼他们 不是吗 长官
You know they're only criminals because you've chosen to call them that, right, sir?
我的天 罗德 你废话的本事倒是见长
My God, Rhodes. Your talent for horseshit rivals my own.
如果不是因为那些协议 幻视就不会离开
If it weren't for those Accords, Vision would've been right here.
我记得你也在协议上签了字的 上校
I remember your signature on those papers, Colonel.
没错
That's right.
但我也为此付出了代价
And I'm pretty sure I paid for that.
你后悔了吗？
You have second thoughts?
现在没了
Not anymore.
国务卿先生
Mr. Secretary.
你们胆子够大的
You got some nerve.
不得不承认
I'll give you that.
你现在是需要胆子的时候
You could use some of that right now.
世界乱成一团
The world's on fire.
你就以为天下大赦了吗？
And you think all is forgiven?
我不需要赦免
I'm not looking for forgiveness.
也不需要你的批准
And I'm way past asking permission.
地球已经被入侵 我们是来对付敌人的
Earth just lost her best defender. So we're here to fight.
如果你要阻止我们的话
And if you wanna stand in our way...
我们也会对付你
we'll fight you too.
逮捕他们
Arrest them.
遵命
All over it.
够上军事法庭的了
That's a court-martial.
真高兴再见到你 队长
It's great to see you, Cap.
我也是 罗德
You too, Rhodey.
嘿
Hey.
你们现在看起来 实在是太狼狈了
Wow. You guys...really look like crap.
这几年来一定很辛苦吧
Must've been a rough couple years.
是啊 毕竟不是住在五星级酒店里
Yeah, well, the hotels weren't exactly five star.
我觉得你们看着挺好的
Uh, I think you look great.
没错 我回来了
Yeah, I'm back.
嗨 布鲁斯
Hi, Bruce.
娜塔莎
Nat.
有点尴尬
This is awkward.
所以说 他们还会再回来的
So we gotta assume they're coming back, right?
而且他们能轻易找到我们
And they can clearly find us.
我们需要调集所有人 克林特人呢
We need all hands on deck. Where's Clint?
内战之后 出于为家庭考虑 他和斯科特妥协了
After the whole Accords situation, he and Scott took a deal. It was too tough
他们目前被软禁在住所
on their families. They're on house arrest.
- 谁是斯科特？ - 蚁人
- Who's Scott? - Ant-Man.
除了蜘蛛侠还有个蚁人？
There's an Ant-Man and a Spider-Man?
言归正传
Okay, look.
灭霸拥有全宇宙最庞大的军队
Thanos has the biggest army in the universe...
他绝不会轻易罢休的 除非他 得到...
and he is not gonna stop until he gets...
幻视的宝石
Vision's stone.
既然如此 我们要保护它
Then we have to protect it.
不 我们该毁掉它
No, we have to destroy it.
长久以来 我一直在研究这块宝石
I've been giving a good deal of thought to this entity in my head.
关于它的元素性质 还有它的构成
About its nature. But also its composition.
我认为当它暴露在
I think if it were exposed
一种足够强大的能量源下
to a sufficiently powerful energy source...
其性质跟宝石能量性质相近 也许
something very similar to its own signature, perhaps...
能破坏它的分子结构
its molecular integrity could fail.
你也会随之被毁
Yeah, and you with it.
我们不能这么做
We're not having this conversation.
毁掉宝石 是阻止灭霸得到它的 唯一办法
Eliminating the stone is the only way to be certain that Thanos can't get it.
可代价是失去你
That's too high a price.
只有你 有能力做到
Only you have the power to pay it.
灭霸会威胁到半个宇宙的生命
Thanos threatens half the universe.
为了阻止他 牺牲一条性命并不算什么
One life cannot stand in the way of defeating him.
不能这样
But it should.
我们不拿性命做交换 幻视
We don't trade lives, Vision.
队长 70年前你也拿自己的性命换回了成千上万人的性命
Captain, 70 years ago, you laid down your life...to save how many millions of people?
那你说 跟现在有什么区别？
Tell me, why is this any different?
因为你或许还有其他选择
Because you might have a choice.
你的思维是一个极其复杂的合成体
Your mind is made up of a complex construct of overlays.
有贾维斯 奥创 托尼 我 还有宝石
Jarvis, Ultron, Tony, me, the stone.
所有思维源在一起相互融合 相互作用
All of them mixed together, all of them learning from one another.
你是说幻视并不只是那块宝石？
You're saying Vision isn't just the stone?
我的意思是 即使取出宝石
I'm saying that if we take out the stone...
幻视也能保留大部分的自我
there's still a whole lot of Vision left.
也许还是最好的那部分
Perhaps the best parts.
这能做到吗？
Can we do that?
我不行 这地方也不行
Not me, not here.
你最好赶快找到合适的人和地方
Well, you better find someone and somewhere fast.
国务卿一定会想办法逮捕你们
Ross isn't just gonna let you guys have your old rooms back.
我知道一个地方
I know somewhere.
(瓦坎达)
国王护卫队和朵拉侍卫队已经准备就绪了
The Kingsguard and the Dora Milaje have been alerted.
边境部落呢？ - 剩下的人都来了
And the Border Tribe? - Those that are left.
派人通知贾巴里部落
Send word to the Jabari as well.
这可不能少了姆巴库
M'Baku likes a good fight.
遵命 陛下
那这个人呢？
And what of this one?
这个人也对战争已经疲倦了
This one may be tired of war.
但白狼已蠢蠢欲动了
But the White Wolf has rested long enough.
敌人在哪？
Where's the fight?
很快就会到来
On its way.
我辅佐灭霸这么久
In all the time I've served Thanos...
从没让他失望过
I have never failed him.
要是等我们到了泰坦
If I were to reach our rendezvous on Titan...
献出时间宝石时 还多了一个碍事的你
with the Time Stone still attached to your vaguely irritating person...
那就是办事不利
there would be judgment.
把宝石
Give me...
交出来
the stone.
你还真是件忠心耿耿的装备
Wow, you're a seriously loyal piece of outerwear, aren't you?
说到忠心...
Yeah, uh, speaking of loyalty...
搞什么
What the...
- 我知道你想说什么 - 你不该在这的
- I know what you're gonna say. - You should not be here.
- 我本来是要回家的 - 我不想听你解释
- I was gonna go home. - I don't wanna hear it.
但是下去距离太远了 而且我也担心你 - 看来必须听了
But it was such a long way down and I just thought about you on the way... - And now I gotta hear it.
然后我被卡在船身上了
...and kinda stuck to the side of the ship.
然后这套战甲好像智能过头了 - 我的天
And this suit is ridiculously intuitive, by the way. - God damn it.
所以我在这儿某种程度上也是你的错
So, if anything, it's kinda your fault that I'm here.
- 你刚刚说什么？ - 我收回刚才的话
- What did you just say? - I take that back.
现在我已经在太空了 - 是的 就是我不想你来的地方
And now, I'm here in space. - Yeah, right where I didn't want you to be.
这不是科尼岛 也不是校园考察
This isn't Coney Island. This isn't a field trip.
这可能有去无回
This is a one-way ticket.
你懂吗？ 别假装你考虑过了 - 我确实考虑过了
You hear me? Don't pretend you thought this through. - No, I did think this through.
你不可能考虑清楚的
You could not have possibly thought this through.
如果邻居们都没了 还怎么当好邻家蜘蛛侠
You can't be a friendly neighborhood Spider-Man...if there's no neighborhood.
好吧 这有点强词夺理 但你懂我的意思
Okay, that didn't really make sense, but you know what I'm trying to say.
好吧 我们遇到点情况
Come on. We got a situation.
看到下面那了吗 他有麻烦
See him down there? He's in trouble.
你有什么计划 - 看见了 让我想想...
What's your plan? - Okay, okay... Uh...
有了 你看过《异形》这个老电影吗？
Okay. Did you ever see this really old movie, Aliens?
很痛苦 是吧？
Painful, aren't they?
它们最初是为微创手术设计的
They were originally designed for microsurgery.
而且任何一根...
And any one of them...
都能瞬间结束你朋友的生命
could end your friend's life in an instant.
先声明 他并不算是我的朋友
I gotta tell you, he's not really my friend.
救他更多是出于职业道德
Saving his life is more of a professional courtesy.
你什么也救不了
You've saved nothing.
你的力量跟我相比 简直微不足道
Your powers are inconsequential compared to mine.
没错 但这孩子看的电影够多
Yeah, but the kid's seen more movies.
等等 那是什么?
Yes! Wait. What are those?
嗨 我们还没正式见过面
Hey, we haven't officially met.
好吧
Cool.
我们得把这艘船掉头
We gotta turn this ship around.
好 这就打算逃走了 想法真好
Yeah, now he wants to run. Great plan.
不 我得保护宝石
No, I want to protect the stone.
你还得感谢我呢 说吧 我听着呢
And I want you to thank me. Now, go ahead. I'm listening.
谢什么？ 差点把我轰进太空里吗？
For what? Nearly blasting me into space?
刚刚是谁救了你的命？ 我
Who just saved your magical ass? Me.
我真不知道你那自大的脑袋是怎么塞进头盔的
I seriously don't know how you fit your head into that helmet.
想想吧 你早该听我的藏起来
Admit it, you should've ducked out when I told you to.
我想帮你 是你自己不听
I tried to bench you. You refused.
我不是给你打工的 不像你生活里的其他人
Unlike everyone else in your life, I don't work for you.
正因如此 我们现在在这个飞行甜甜圈上 离地球十万八千里 没有后援
And due to that fact, we're now in a flying doughnut...billions of miles from Earth with no backup.
- 我就是后援 - 不 你只能算偷渡的
- I'm backup. - No, you're a stowaway.
大人们正说话呢
The adults are talking.
不好意思 我不明白你们的关系
I'm sorry, I'm confused as to the relationship here.
你是他的监护人吗？ - 不
What is he, your ward? - No.
- 顺便介绍下 我叫彼得 - 斯特兰奇医生
- I'm Peter, by the way. - Doctor Strange.
奇异博士和斯特兰奇医生的英语都是Doctor Strange，漫画里也有搞混的桥段
噢 我们要用绰号的吗
Oh, you're using our made-up names. Um...
那我叫蜘蛛侠
I'm Spider-Man, then.
这艘船正在自动修正航线 是自动驾驶
This ship is self-correcting its course. Thing's on autopilot.
我们能操作吗？ 飞回地球
Can we control it? Fly us home?
- 斯塔克 - 嗯？
- Stark? - Yeah.
你能带我们回地球吗？ - 我听见了
Can you get us home? - Yeah, I heard you.
我不确定我们该不该回去
I'm thinking I'm not so sure we should.
无论如何我们都不能让灭霸拿到宝石
Under no circumstances can we bring the Time Stone to Thanos.
你恐怕还不明白事情多么严重 - 多么严重
I don't think you quite understand - what's at stake here.
不 是你不明白
What? No. It's you who doesn't understand...
灭霸萦绕我的脑海六年了
that Thanos has been inside my head for six years.
就是自从他入侵纽约开始 现在他回来了
Since he sent an army to New York and now he's back.
我不知道该怎么办
And I don't know what to do.
所以我不确定 在谁的地盘上作战会更有胜算
So I'm not so sure if it's a better plan to fight him on our turf or his...
但你也看到了 他们的实力 他们的能耐
but you saw what they did, what they can do.
至少灭霸不会料到我们去找他
At least on his turf, he's not expecting it.
所以我觉得我们应该主动出击
So I say we take the fight to him.
博士
Doctor.
你赞同吗？
Do you concur?
好吧 斯塔克 我们去找他
All right, Stark. We go to him.
但你要明白
But you have to understand...
如果要我选择救你 或那孩子 或是时间宝石
if it comes to saving you or the kid or the Time Stone...
我会毫不犹豫地舍弃你们两个
I will not hesitate to let either of you die.
我必须如此 因为这事关整个宇宙
I can't, because the universe depends on it.
好 很好 道德模范
Nice. Good, moral compass.
我们说明了
We're straight.
好吧 孩子
All right, kid.
你现在是复仇者了
You're an Avenger now.
我想你应该饿了吧
I thought you might be hungry.
我一直讨厌那椅子
I always hated that chair.
你跟我说过了
So I've been told.
即便如此 我还是希望有一天你能坐上去
Even so, I'd hoped you'd sit in it one day.
我恨这个房间
I hated this room.
这艘船
This ship.
我恨我的生活
I hated my life.
你也跟我说过了
You told me that too.
天天说
Every day.
说了快20年
For almost 20 years.
你掳走我的时候我还是个孩子
I was a child when you took me.
我救了你
I saved you.
不
No.
我们在故乡星球生活的很幸福
No. We were happy on my home planet.
睡觉时忍受着饥饿 乞讨着剩饭过日子
Going to bed hungry...scrounging for scraps.
星球的生态濒临崩溃 是我避免了灾难发生
Your planet was on the brink of collapse. I'm the one who stopped that.
你知道那个星球后来怎么样了吗？
Do you know what's happened since then?
孩子一出生
The children born...
就能吃饱穿暖 在蓝天下自由玩耍 像天堂一样
have known nothing but full bellies and clear skies. It's a paradise.
因为半个星球的人都你屠杀了
Because you murdered half the planet.
为了救赎的一点小代价罢了
A small price to pay for salvation.
你是个疯子 - 小家伙 这只是个简单的算术问题
You're insane. - Little one, it's a simple calculus.
这个宇宙是有限的 资源也是有限的
This universe is finite, its resources finite.
如果生命不加以控制 最后就会灭绝
If life is left unchecked, life will cease to exist.
需要有人来修正它 - 你根本不明白
It needs correction. - You don't know that!
我是唯一一个明白的人
I'm the only one who knows that.
至少 我是唯一一个愿意付诸行动的人
At least, I'm the only one with the will to act on it.
曾经...
For a time...
你也有同样的理想
you had that same will...
并为我而战 女儿
as you fought by my side. Daughter.
我不是你的女儿
I'm not your daughter.
我憎恨你教过我的所有东西
Everything I hate about myself you taught me.
正是这些 让你成为整个银河系最凶狠的女战士
And, in doing so, made you the fiercest woman in the galaxy.
这就是为什么我相信你能找到灵魂宝石
That's why I trusted you to find the Soul Stone.
很抱歉让你失望了
I'm sorry I disappointed you.
我的确很失望
I am disappointed.
不是因为你没找到
But not because you didn't find it.
而是因为你找到了
But because you did.
却撒了谎
And you lied.
星云！
Nebula.
不要这样
Don't do this.
不久以前 你妹妹潜入这艘飞船里想要暗杀我
Some time ago, your sister snuck aboard this ship to kill me.
求你了 不要这样 - 她差点就得手了
Please don't do this. - And very nearly succeeded.
所以我把她带过来了
So I brought her here.
好好聊一聊
To talk.
住手 快住手
Stop. Stop it.
我以生命发誓...
I swear to you on my life.
我从来没有找到过灵魂宝石
I never found the Soul Stone.
读取记忆数据...
Accessing memory files.
你知道他会怎么做
You know what he's about to do.
他已经准备好了 他要拿到宝石
He's finally ready, and he's going for the stones.
- 所有宝石 - 他拿不到所有的
- All of them. - He can never get them all.
他会的
He will!
不会的 星云
He can't, Nebula.
因为我找到了灵魂宝石的地图
Because I found the map to the Soul Stone...
然后我把它烧了 我烧了
and I burned it to ash. I burned it.
你的强大
You're strong.
是我教的
Me.
你的大度
You're generous.
是我教的
Me.
但我从来没教过你撒谎
But I never taught you to lie.
所以你压根不会撒谎
That's why you're so bad at it.
灵魂宝石在哪？
Where is the Soul Stone?
沃米尔
Vormir!
宝石在沃米尔星
The stone is on Vormir.
带我去
Show me.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
尿杯子里 我们不会看的 有什么好看的
Tinkle in the cup. We're not looking. What's there to see?
小树枝而已 谁没见过小树枝啊
What's a twig? Everybody's seen a twig before.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
你可以把杯子里的东西倒到太空里 然后杯子还能再用一遍
Tree, pour what's in the cup out into space and go in the cup again.
你懂格鲁特语言？
You speak Groot?
对 在阿斯加德 是门选修课
Yes, they taught it on Asgard. It was an elective.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
等到了 你们就知道了
You'll know when we're close.
尼达维的熔炉 使用了一颗中子星的炙热能量
Nidavellir's forge harnesses the blazing power of a neutron star.
我的锤子就是在这打造的
It's the birthplace of my hammer.
而且棒极了
It's truly awesome.
好吧 是时候当知心舰长了
Okay, time to be the captain.
弟弟死了是吗
So, dead brother, huh?
唉 一定不好受
Yeah, that could be annoying.
他之前也假死过几次
Well, he's been dead before.
但这回 他可能是真的死了
But, no, this time I think it really might be true.
你之前说你姐姐和父亲... - 都死了
And you said your sister and your dad? - Both dead.
母亲还在吧？
But still got a mom, though?
被黑暗精灵杀了
Killed by a dark elf.
好朋友呢？ - 被刺穿了心脏
A best friend? - Stabbed through the heart.
你确定你能胜任这次任务吗？
You sure you're up to this particular murder mission?
当然了 复仇 怒火 失去 悲伤
Absolutely. Rage and vengeance, anger, loss, regret...
都是我巨大的精神力量
they're all tremendous motivators.
它们让我心无旁骛 所以我完全可以胜任
They really clear the mind. So I'm good to go.
好吧 但是这个灭霸
Yeah, but this Thanos we're talkin' about...
他可是宇宙最强的
he's the toughest there is.
但他还没跟我决斗 - 他有
- Well, he's never fought me. - Yeah, he has.
他没跟我决斗过两次
He's never fought me twice.
别忘了 我会拿到一把新锤子
And I'm getting a new hammer, don't forget.
那这锤子最好足够厉害
It better be some hammer.
你知道 我已经1500岁了
You know, I'm 1,500 years old.
杀掉的敌人有这岁数的两倍
I've killed twice as many enemies as that.
他们每个人都想杀掉我 但没有一个人得手
And every one of them would've rather killed me, but none succeeded.
我还活着是命运注定的
I'm only alive because fate wants me alive.
灭霸只不过是又一个这样的敌人
Thanos is just the latest in a long line of bastards...
他也同样会死在我的手上
and he'll be the latest to feel my vengeance.
命运注定
Fate wills it so.
但如果你猜错了呢？
And what if you're wrong?
如果我错了的话 那么...
If I'm wrong, then...
我还有什么可失去的？
what more could I lose?
我有好多
I could lose a lot.
我有好多不想失去
Me, personally, I could lose a lot.
好吧
Okay.
如果命运安排让你杀了那个混蛋
If fate does want you to kill that crapsack...
你可不能睁一只眼闭一只眼
you're gonna need more than one stupid eyeball.
- 这是什么？ - 你觉得呢？
- What's this? - What's it look like?
有个混混在康特阿克夏跟我赌博赌输了
Some jerk lost a bet with me on Contraxia.
他赌了这只眼睛？
He gave you his eye?
没有 他赌的钱
No, he gave me 100 credits.
那天晚上我溜进他房间偷了这个眼球
I snuck into his room later that night and stole his eye.
多谢了 暖心小兔子
Thank you, sweet rabbit.
是我就先洗一洗再用
I would've washed that.
要把这东西带出赌场就只能塞在我的.....
The only way I could sneak it off Contraxia was up my...
嘿 我们到了
Hey, we're here!
我觉得这眼球不管用 看什么都很暗
I don't think this thing works. Everything seems dark.
恐怕不是眼球的问题
It ain't the eye.
不大对劲
Something's wrong.
中子星熄灭了
The star's gone out.
星环也被冻住了
And the rings are frozen.
(尼达维)
希望这些矮人锻造的水平比打扫卫生的水平高
I hope these dwarves are better at forging than they are cleaning.
他们也许意识到自己住在了宇宙中的一个垃圾堆里
Maybe they realized that they live in a junk pile in the middle of space.
熔炉几个世纪都没熄灭过
This forge hasn't gone dark in centuries.
你说过灭霸有个手套对吧？
You said Thanos had a gauntlet, right?
是啊 怎么了？ - 就像这样的吗？
Yes, why? - It look anything like that?
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
快回到飞船里去
Go back to the pod.
伊崔 慢着 住手
Eitri, wait! Stop!
住手
Stop.
索尔？
Thor?
这里发生了什么？
What happened here?
你应该保护我们的
You were supposed to protect us.
阿斯加德应该保护我们的
Asgard was supposed to protect us.
阿斯加德 已经被摧毁了
Asgard is destroyed.
伊崔 那个手套 你做了什么？
Eitri, the glove. What did you do?
曾经有三百个矮人住在星环上
300 dwarves lived on this ring.
我以为答应了他的要求 我们就能够逃过一劫
I thought if I did what he asked, they'd be safe.
我打造了他想要的
I made what he wanted.
一个能控制宝石能量的装置
A device capable of harnessing the power of the stones.
结果他还是杀了所有的人
Then he killed everyone anyway.
除了我
All except me.
他说 你的生命属于你
"Your life is yours," he said.
但你的双手 属于我
"But your hands are mine alone."
伊崔 这不在于你的双手
Eitri, this isn't about your hands.
你打造过的所有武器
Every weapon you've ever designed,
每一把斧头 锤子 宝剑 这些都储存在你的大脑里
every axe, hammer, sword...it's all inside your head.
我能理解你的绝望 相信我 我知道你的心情
Now, I know it feels like all hope is lost. Trust me, I know.
但我们一起 可以消灭灭霸
But together, you and I, we can kill Thanos.
曼蒂斯 听清楚
Mantis, listen very carefully.
我需要你们赶到泰坦星跟我回合
I need you to meet me on Titan.
什么情况？ - 我想我们到了
Hey, what's going on? - I think we're here.
这艘船应该没有自动降落功能
I don't think this rig has a self-park function.
手伸到方向装置里 把这扣上
Get your hand inside the steering gimbal. Close those around it.
- 懂了吗？ - 懂了
- You understand? - Yep, got it.
这东西是给大块头设计的 我们得一起操作 - 好的 准备
This was meant for one big guy, so we gotta move at the same time. - Okay, okay. Ready.
我们得转向 转向 转向
We might wanna turn. Turn! Turn! Turn!
(泰坦星)
你还好吧？
You all right?
刚刚好险
That was close.
我欠你一次
I owe you one.
我先说好 如果有抱脸虫 在我的体内产卵
Let me just say, if aliens wind up implanting eggs in my chest or something...
然后我吃了你们的话 我很抱歉
and I eat one of you, I'm sorry.
现在开始 我不想再听到你引用流行文化 明白了吗？
I do not want another single pop culture reference out of you for the rest of the trip. You understand?
我只想说 有什么东西过来了
I'm trying to say that something is coming.
灭霸！
Thanos!
不要在我体内产卵
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Please don't put your eggs in me!
别动 小丑
Stay down, clown.
死吧 死亡魔毯
Die, blanket of death!
呆在原地 都他妈冷静
Everybody stay where you are. Chill the eff out.
我先问一个问题
I'm gonna ask you this one time.
卡魔拉在哪
Where is Gamora?
我有个更好的问题 卡魔拉是谁？
Yeah. I'll do you one better. Who's Gamora?
我有个更好的问题 为什么都问卡魔拉？
I'll do you one better. Why is Gamora?
告诉我她在哪 不然我保证 这只小怪物被炸成薯条
Tell me where the girl is or I swear to you I'm gonna French fry this little freak.
那你来啊 你敢动我的人我就轰了他 来啊
Let's do it. You shoot my guy and I'll blast him. Let's go!
开枪吧 奎尔 我能扛得住
Do it, Quill! I can take it.
- 不 他扛不了的 - 她说的对 你扛不了的
- No, he can't take it! - She's right. You can't.
是吗 不打算告诉我卡魔拉在哪是吧 行啊
Oh, yeah? You don't wanna tell me where she is? That's fine.
我就杀了你们三个人 然后再亲自把灭霸揍到开口
I'll kill all three of you and I'll beat it out of Thanos myself.
就从你开始 - 等一下 灭霸？
Starting with you. - Wait, what, Thanos?
好了 这次轮到我提问了
All right, let me ask you this one time.
你为哪个主子效力？
What master do you serve?
哪个主子? 我难道该回答 耶稣?
What master do I serve? What am I supposed to say, "Jesus"?
你来自地球 - 不 我来自密苏里
You're from Earth. - I'm not from Earth, I'm from Missouri.
那就在地球上 笨蛋 跟我们打什么?
Yeah, that's on Earth, dipshit. What are you hassling us for?
所以你们不是灭霸一伙的?
So you're not with Thanos?
灭霸一伙的?
With Thanos?
不 我是来杀他的
No, I'm here to kill Thanos.
他抓走了我女朋友 等等 你们是谁
He took my girl. Wait, who are you?
我们是复仇者
- We're the Avengers, man. - Oh.
你们是索尔说的那群人
You're the ones Thor told us about.
你认识索尔
You know Thor?
是的
Yeah.
高个子 长得不帅 需要拯救
Tall guy, not that good-looking, needed saving.
他现在在哪儿?
Where is he now?
这就是计划? 我们要用板砖拍灭霸?
This is the plan? We're gonna hit him with a brick?
这是个模具
It's a mold.
国王级武器
A king's weapon.
也就是阿斯加德最强大的武器
Meant to be the greatest in Asgard.
理论上 它甚至可以召唤彩虹桥
In theory, it could even summon the Bifrost.
它有名字吗？
Did it have a name?
风暴战斧
Stormbreaker.
有点过头了
That's a bit much.
我们该怎么做?
So how do we make it?
你需要重新点燃熔炉
You'll have to restart the forge.
唤醒已经熄灭的中子星核心
Awaken the heart of a dying star.
兔子 启动飞船
Rabbit, fire up the pod.
这星球上究竟发生了什么
The hell happened to this planet?
偏离自转轴8度
It's eight degrees off its axis.
到处都是引力场
Gravitational pull is all over the place.
我们有一个优势 就是知道他会来找我们
Yeah, we got one advantage. He's coming to us.
得好好利用 好吧 我有个计划
We'll use it. All right, I have a plan.
至少有个大体思路
Or at least the beginnings of one.
很简单 把他引来 放倒他 拿到我们需要的东西
It's pretty simple. We draw him in, pin him down, get what we need.
绝不要和他过多纠缠 我们只要手套
Definitely don't wanna dance with this guy. We just want the gauntlet.
你在打哈欠吗?
Are you yawning?
在我讲解计划的时候?
In the middle of this, while I'm breaking it down? Huh?
我刚才讲的什么?
Did you hear what I said?
你说“有一个计划”之后我就没在听了
I stopped listening after you said, "We need a plan."
Mr.Clean：朗白先生，美国保洁品牌，其封面为一光头男子
朗白先生还沉浸在自己的世界里
Okay, Mr. Clean is on his own page.
提前计划 不是他们的做事风格
See, "not winging it" isn't really what they do.
那他们的风格是什么？
Uh, what exactly is it that they do?
兵来土掩 水来将挡 - 没错
Kick names, take ass. - Yeah, that's right.
好了 大家先站过来 好吗？
All right, just get over here, please.
勋爵先生 能让你的人围过来吗?
Mr. Lord, can you get your folks to circle up?
不用勋爵 叫我星爵就好
"Mr. Lord." Star-Lord is fine.
我们必须联合起来 如果我们都只是想着和他拼命...
We gotta coalesce.'Cause if all we come at him with is a plucky attitude...
兄弟 别说什么拼命 我们不懂那是什么意思
Dude, don't call us plucky. We don't know what it means.
好吧 我们是比较乐观 我喜欢你的计划
All right, we're optimistic, yes. I like your plan.
但是 太烂了 所以让我来计划
Except it sucks, so let me do the plan...
这样才可能是个好计划
and that way it might be really good.
跟他说说你斗舞拯救宇宙那次
Tell him about the dance-off to save the universe.
- 什么斗舞? - 不是...
- What dance-off? - It's nothing.
凯文·贝肯主演的歌舞片
像《浑身是劲》那个电影里那种？ - 对 就像《浑身是劲》那样的
Like in Footloose, the movie? - Exactly like Footloose.
它还是史上最伟大的电影吗？
Is it still the greatest movie in history?
从来都不是
It never was.
别助长他 好吗？
Don't encourage this, all right?
这位飞侠哥顿帮不上我们什么 - 飞侠哥顿？
- Okay. - We're getting no help from Flash Gordon here. - Flash Gordon?
飞侠哥顿：八十年代科幻片，同样是地球人主角闯荡太空
那我得说 这可是种赞美
By the way, that's a compliment.
别忘了 我只有一半的人类血统
Don't forget, I'm half human.
所以我只有50%的愚蠢 但你们是百分百的愚蠢
So that 50% of me that's stupid...that's 100% you.
你的数学真让我开眼界
Your math is blowing my mind.
打断一下
Excuse me.
请问你的朋友经常这样吗？
But does your friend often do that?
斯特兰奇 你还好吗？
Strange, we all right?
你恢复了 还好吗
You're back. You're all right.
你刚刚那是怎么了？
- Hi. - Hey, what was that?
我穿越了时间 观察各种未来走势
I went forward in time to view alternate futures.
看到了这场大战所有可能的结局
To see all the possible outcomes of the coming conflict.
你看了多少种结局？
How many did you see?
14,000,605种
14,000,605.
我们赢了几次？
How many did we win?
一次
One.
(沃弥尔)
宝石最好是在那儿
The stone had better be up there.
为了你妹妹的性命
For your sister's sake.
欢迎到来 灭霸 厄洛斯之子
Welcome, Thanos, son of Alars.
卡魔拉 灭霸之女
Gamora, daughter of Thanos.
你认识我们？
You know us?
我的诅咒就是认识每一位到此之人
It is my curse to know all who journey here.
灵魂宝石在哪里？
Where is the Soul Stone?
你应该知道的 得到它需要沉重的代价
You should know...it extracts a terrible price.
我准备好了
I am prepared.
我们最开始都是这么认为
We all think that at first.
但我们都错了
We are all wrong.
你为什么会如此了解这个地方？
How is it you know this place so well?
在很久以前 我也曾追寻过宝石
A lifetime ago, I, too, sought the stones.
我甚至曾把一颗宝石握在掌中
I even held one in my hand.
但它抛弃了我 将我流放至此
But it cast me out, banished me here.
指引别人寻找我无法拥有的珍宝
Guiding others to a treasure I cannot possess.
你所寻找的 就坐落在你的脚下
What you seek lies in front of you.
你所恐惧的也在那里
As does what you fear.
怎么讲 - 代价
What's this? - The price.
灵魂宝石在无限宝石中占据着非常特殊的地位
Soul holds a special place among the Infinity Stones.
你可以称之为一种智慧
You might say it has a certain wisdom.
告诉我它需要什么
Tell me what it needs.
为了确保每一个拥有宝石的人 都能理解它的力量
To ensure that whoever possesses it...understands its power...
宝石要求一份献祭
the stone demands a sacrifice.
献祭什么？
Of what?
若要得到灵魂宝石 必须失去自己的挚爱
In order to take the stone, you must lose that which you love.
以灵魂 换灵魂
A soul...for a soul.
我这一生 都梦想着有一天
All my life, I dreamed of a day...
有一刻
a moment...
能看到你自食恶果
when you got what you deserved.
然而我总是不能得偿所愿
And I was always so disappointed.
但现在...
But now...
你草菅人命 虐杀无辜
You kill and torture...
却还美其名曰仁慈
and you call it mercy.
如今宇宙对你做出宣判
The universe has judged you.
你祈求它的赏赐 却被它拒绝
You asked it for a prize, and it told you no.
你已一败涂地
You failed.
你想知道为什么吗？
And do you wanna know why?
因为你不爱任何东西
Because you love nothing.
不爱任何人
No one.
不
No.
真的吗？
Really?
泪水？
Tears?
他非为为自己流泪
They're not for him.
不
No.
这根本不是爱
This isn't love.
我曾一度无视自己的命运
I ignored my destiny once.
我不能再重蹈覆辙
I cannot do that again.
就算...是为了你
Even for you.
对不起了 小家伙
I'm sorry, little one.
不
No!
高度降至2600 航向0-3-0
Drop to 2600, heading 0-3-0.
希望你说的是正确的
I hope you're right about this.
否则我们就要机毁人亡了
Or we're gonna land a lot faster than you want to.
当你说瓦坎达将对全世界开放时
When you said we were going to open Wakanda to the rest of the world...
情况跟我想得可不太一样
this is not what I imagined.
你想的是什么样的？
And what did you imagine?
奥运会 或者开家星巴克
The Olympics. Maybe even a Starbucks.
我们需要鞠躬吗？
Should we bow?
当然 他可是位国王
Yeah, he's a king.
我好像总在给你添麻烦
Seems like I'm always thanking you for something.
你在搞什么？
What are you doing?
我们这儿没这习俗
Uh, we don't do that here.
敌方部队大概有多少规模
So how big of an assault should we expect?
先生 我认为你应该准备应对非常猛烈的袭击
Uh, sir, I think you should expect quite a big assault.
我们这边呢？
How we looking?
我的国王护卫队会参战
You will have my Kingsguard,
还有边境部落 朵拉侍卫队 以及
the Border Tribe, the Dora Milaje, and...
一个还算稳定的百岁老人
And a semi-stable 100-year-old man.
你怎么样 巴基
How you been, Buck?
还行吧 毕竟都快世界末日了
Uh, not bad, for the end of the world.
这是个多层晶体结构
The structure is polymorphic.
没错 我们需要排序组合每一个神经元
Right, we had to attach each neuron non-sequentially.
你们为什么不尝试重新编辑神经元突触 使他们协同工作呢
Why didn't you just reprogram the synapses to work collectively?
因为...我们没想到这种方法
Because we didn't think of it.
我相信你们已经尽力了
I'm sure you did your best.
你能做到吗？
Can you do it?
可以 但是有超过两万亿个神经元存在于此
Yes, but there are more than two trillion neurons here.
一点微小偏差就会导致一连串的回路故障
One misalignment could cause a cascade of circuit failures.
这需要很久 哥哥
It will take time, brother.
要多久？
How long?
尽可能争取多一点时间吧
As long as you can give me.
不明物体进入了大气层
Something's entered the atmosphere.
队长 我们这有情况
Hey, Cap, we got a situation here.
上帝 我爱死这里了
God, I love this place.
别高兴太早 各位 更多目标降落在穹顶外
Yeah, don't start celebrating yet, guys. We got more incoming outside the dome.
来不及了
It's too late.
我们必须立刻毁掉原石
We need to destroy the stone now.
幻视 你给我躺回去
Vision, get your ass back on the table.
我们会拖住他们
We will hold them off.
旺达 一旦将宝石取下来
Wanda, as soon as that stone's out of his head...
马上毁掉它
you blow it to hell.
我会的
I will.
立刻疏散市民 启动全部防御
Evacuate the city. Engage all defenses.
给这个人拿副盾牌
And get this man a shield.
我认为你没搞清这里的状况
I don't think you get the scientifics here.
这些环体太大了 要想移动它们
These rings are gigantic. You wanna get them moving...
你需要借助更大的东西 来带动它们
you're gonna need something a lot bigger to yank 'em loose.
- 交给我吧 - 交给你？
- Leave that to me. - Leave it to you?
兄弟 你现在在太空 就拿着一根绳子
Buddy, you're in space. All you got is a rope and a...
启动引擎
Fire the engines!
加大马力 兔子
More power, rabbit!
干得漂亮 小子
Well done, boy.
这才是尼达维
That's Nidavellir.
该死 - 怎么该死了？
Damn it. "Damn it"? What's "damn it"?
- 机械装置损坏了
The mechanism is crippled.
- 什么？ - 虹圈关闭的话 我没法熔炼金属
- What? - With the iris closed, I can't heat the metal.
需要加热多长时间？
How long will it take to heat it?
几分钟 也可能更久 怎么了
A few minutes, maybe more. Why?
我去把它撑开 - 这是去送死
I'm gonna hold it open. - That's suicide.
没有那把战斧 去找灭霸也是死
So is facing Thanos without that axe.
你那边情况如何 布鲁斯？
How we looking, Bruce?
我觉得我已经掌握窍门了
Yeah, I think I'm getting the hang of it.
这简直太棒了
Wow! This is amazing, man.
感觉自己不用变身 就成了浩克.
It's like being the Hulk without actually...
我没事 我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
发现两个热感信号 在树林方向出现
I've got two heat signatures breaking through the tree line.
必胜...
谢谢你愿意和我们并肩作战 - 不用谢我的兄弟
Thank you for standing with us.
你那个伙伴去哪了？
Where's your other friend?
你们会血债血偿的
You will pay for his life with yours.
灭霸会拿到那块宝石
Thanos will have that stone.
那是不可能的
That's not gonna happen.
你们在瓦坎达的领土上
You are in Wakanda now.
灭霸除了鲜血和废墟 什么都别想得到
Thanos will have nothing but dust and blood.
我们不在乎流血
We have blood to spare.
他们投降了？
They surrender?
并没有
Not exactly.
坚守阵地...
什么鬼东西？
What the hell?
看来我们把她惹急了
Looks like we pissed her off.
他们这是在自杀
They're killing themselves.
防御阵型...
攻击
看到这些怪物的牙有多大了吗？
You see the teeth on those things?
你后退 山姆 别把你的翅膀给烧了
All right, back up, Sam. You're gonna get your wings singed.
队长 如果这些怪物 从我们后方突破防御罩
Cap, if these things circle the perimeter and get in behind us...
那幻视就危险了
there's nothing between them and Vision.
那就必须把他们留在我们这
Then we better keep 'em in front of us.
我们该怎么做？
How do we do that?
打开防护罩
We open the barrier.
听我的命令  解除西北方向17区的防护罩
On my signal, open North-West Section Seventeen.
请求确认命令  国王陛下
Requesting confirmation, My King.
您是说解除防护罩吗？
You said open the barrier?
照我说的做
On my signal.
这将是瓦坎达的末日
This will be the end of Wakanda.
那也是历史上最壮烈的末日
Then it will be the noblest ending in history.
解除防御
瓦坎达万岁！
Wakanda forever!
就是现在！
Now!
还需要多久 苏睿？
How much longer, Shuri?
我这才刚刚开始 哥哥
I've barely begun, brother.
你最好加快进度了
You might want to pick up the pace.
众英烈  请赐予我力量
Allfathers, give me strength.
你要明白 小子 整个星球的能量都会集中到你身上的
You understand, boy? You're about to take the full force of a star.
你会没命的
It'll kill you.
除非我死了
Only if I die.
是啊
Yes.
没命就是这个意思
That's what killing you means.
坚持住 坚持住 索尔！
Hold it! Hold it, Thor!
索尔 说句话 快醒醒
Thor! Say something. Come on.
索尔  你还好吗？
Thor, you okay?
我想他快不行了
I think he's dying.
他需要战斧
He needs the axe!
斧柄在哪？
Where's the handle?
小树 帮我找个斧柄
Tree, help me find the handle!
他们数量太多了
There's too many of 'em!
你们要完蛋了
You guys are so screwed now!
灭霸 给我滚出来
Bring me Thanos!
灭霸 果然人如其名
You're much more of a Thanos.
看来乌木喉已经死了
I take it the Maw is dead.
这一天的代价还真是沉重
This day extracts a heavy toll.
不过  他也算完成了任务
Still, he accomplished his mission.
说不定你会后悔的
You may regret that.
你现在还要跟一位秘术大师交手
He brought you face-to-face with the Master of the Mystic Arts.
你认为这里是什么地方？
And where do you think he brought you?
我猜猜看 你的故乡？
Let me guess. Your home?
曾经是
It was.
而且曾经很美
And it was beautiful.
泰坦星跟大多数星球一样
Titan was like most planets.
人口爆炸 而资源却正在枯竭
Too many mouths, not enough to go around.
后来 当大家走投无路的时候 我提出了一个解决方案
And when we faced extinction, I offered a solution.
种族屠杀
Genocide.
是随机的 不夹私情  无论贫富贵贱
But random, dispassionate, fair to rich and poor alike.
他们说我是个疯子
They called me a madman.
而灾难的到来我预想的分毫不差
And what I predicted came to pass.
恭喜你 成为了一个预言家
Congratulations, you're a prophet.
我只是个幸存者
I'm a survivor.
是想要杀掉几万亿人的幸存者
Who wants to murder trillions.
有了六块宝石 我只要打个响指
With all six stones, I could simply snap my fingers.
他们就将没有痛苦的灰飞烟灭 我称此举为仁慈
They would all cease to exist. I call that mercy.
之后呢？
And then what?
之后我可以隐退了
I'd finally rest...
在一片祥和的宇宙欣赏日出
and watch the sun rise on a grateful universe.
最艰难的决定需要最坚强的意志
The hardest choices require the strongest wills.
你会发现我们有着相同坚强的意志
I think you'll find our will equal to yours.
"我们"？
Our?
小菜一碟 奎尔
Piece of cake, Quill.
没错 如果你的目标是激怒他的话
Yeah, if your goal was to piss him off.
蛛网射脸的一幕致敬了漫画
嘭！
Boom!
别让他握起拳头
Don't let him close his fist.
看我的
Magic.
魔法
More magic.
魔法踢
Magic with a kick.
魔法...
Magic with a...
小虫子
Insect!
你早应该杀了我
You should've killed me.
你本来就是堆没用的零件
It would've been a waste of parts!
卡魔拉在哪？
Where's Gamora?
"西托拉克红带"
控制住了吗？坚持住
Is he under? Don't let up.
快一点 他太强了
Be quick. He is very strong.
帕克 过来帮忙 这边
Parker, help! Get over here.
她撑不住多久的 我们得快点
She can't hold him much longer. Let's go.
我们得把他手掌掰开 才能取下来
We gotta open his fingers to get it off.
还以为你很难抓呢
I thought you'd be hard to catch.
别忘了 这可是我的计划
For the record, this was my plan.
现在威风不起来了吧
You're not so strong now, huh?
卡魔拉在哪？
Where is Gamora?
是我的卡魔拉 - 狗屁
My Gamora. - No, bullshit!
她在哪？
Where is she?
他很痛苦 - 很好
He is in anguish. - Good.
他...他在哀悼
He... He mourns.
一个怪物还哀悼什么？
What does this monster have to mourn?
卡魔拉...
Gamora.
什么？
What?
他带她去了沃米尔星
He took her to Vormir.
他带着灵魂宝石回来了
He came back with the Soul Stone.
但她没回来
But she didn't.
奎尔 你现在得保持冷静 明白吗？
Okay, Quill, you gotta cool it right now. You understand?
别 别冲动 手套就快拿下来了
Don't, don't. Don't engage. We almost got this off!
告诉我她在撒谎
Tell me she's lying.
混蛋 告诉我你没有那么做
Asshole, tell me you didn't do it!
我必须这么做...
I had to.
不 你没有 你没有
No, you didn't. No, you didn't.
- 不 你没有！- 奎尔
- No, you didn't! - Quill!
住手！ 住手！
Hey, stop! Hey, stop! Stop!
住手！
Hey, stop! Stop!
下来了 下来了 我摘下来了
It's coming, it's coming. I got it, I got it!
噢 天啊
Oh, God.
来尝尝子弹吧 傻狗们
Come and get some, space dogs!
来啊 受死 受死 吃老子一枪！
Come on! Get some! Get some! Come on! Get some!
- 这枪多少钱？- 非卖品
- How much for the gun? - Not for sale.
好吧 那这手臂多少钱？
Okay. How much for the arm?
那胳膊老子要定了
Oh, I'll get that arm.
新发型？
New haircut?
我注意到你在模仿我的胡子
Noticed you've copied my beard.
介绍一下 这是我一个朋友 小树苗
By the way, this is a friend of mine, Tree.
我是格鲁特
I am Groot.
我是史蒂夫·罗杰斯
I am Steve Rogers.
撤退 马上撤退
Fall back! Fall back, now!
山姆 集中火力到左翼上
Focus that fire on the left flank, Sam.
我知道
I'm doing it.
她为什么不早点出场？
Why was she up there all this time?
她出来参战了 动手
She's on the field. Take it.
伙计们 幻视那边有危险
Guys, we got a Vision situation here.
- 谁去支援一下幻视
Somebody get to Vision!
- 我去 - 我马上来
- I got him! - On my way.
他将一个人孤独死去 你也一样
He'll die alone. As will you.
她可不是一个人
She's not alone.
不 不 你们别想
Oh, no, you don't.
这可不会像纽约那次一样了
This isn't gonna be like New York, pal.
这套战甲可是把浩克都暴打过的
This suit's already kicked the crap outta the Hulk.
什么 不 不
What? No! No!
各位 幻视需要立即支援
Guys! Vision needs backup, now!
浩克 我知道你总喜欢在最后时刻才出场
Hulk? Hulk, I know you like making your entrance at the last second.
现在就是了 这是最后 最后的时刻了
Well, this is it, man. This is the last, last second.
浩克 浩克 浩克
Hulk! Hulk! Hulk!
不
No!
去你的 你这个绿色的大混蛋
Oh, screw you, you big, green asshole!
我自己来
I'll do it myself!
来吧
Come on! Yeah!
再见了
See ya!
浩克 我们得好好聊聊了 伙计
Hulk, we got a lot to figure out, pal.
还以为你有多么厉害
I thought you were formidable, machine.
但你就要死了 像凡人一样
But you're dying, like any man.
快离开这儿！
Get outta here!
走
Go!
这可真够恶心的
That was really gross.
我不是叫你走吗
I thought I told you to go.
我们不拿性命做交换 队长
We don't trade lives, Captain.
我接住你了 还有你
I got you. I got you.
抱歉 我想不起你们的名字了
I'm sorry I can't remember anybody's names.
"艾克恩之形"
你这个术士 花样倒不少
You're full of tricks, wizard.
但你没来得及用上你最强的武器
Yet you never once used your greatest weapon.
假的
A fake.
你再拿卫星砸我 我就不客气了
You throw another moon at me, and I'm gonna lose it.
斯塔克
Stark.
你认识我？ - 认识
You know me? - I do.
你不是唯一被知识诅咒的人
You're not the only one cursed with knowledge.
我唯一的诅咒是你
My only curse is you.
来吧
Come on!
只让我流了一滴血吗
All that for a drop of blood.
你值得尊敬 斯塔克
You have my respect, Stark.
当我事成之后 还是会有一半人类存活的
When I'm done, half of humanity will still be alive.
我希望他们还能记得你
I hope they remember you.
住手
Stop.
饶他一命
Spare his life...
我就把宝石给你
and I will give you the stone.
别耍花样
No tricks.
别给
Don't.
只差一颗了
One to go.
他在哪？
Where is he?
我们输了吗？
Did we just lose?
你为什么要给他？
Why would you do that?
我们已经到最后时刻了
We're in the endgame now.
必胜...
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
怎么了？
What? What is it?
他来了
He's here.
所有人 到我这里 准备迎敌
Everyone, on my position. We have incoming.
怎么回事
What the hell?
队长 就是他
Cap. That's him.
集中注意 保持警惕
Eyes up. Stay sharp.
旺达 是时候了
Wanda. It's time.
不
No.
他们阻止不了灭霸 但我们可以
They can't stop him, Wanda, but we can.
看着我 只有你有有能力摧毁宝石
Look at me. You have the power to destroy the stone.
别说了 - 你必须要...拜托了
Don't. - You must do it. Wanda, please.
我们没有时间了
We are out of time.
我做不到
I can't.
你可以 你可以的
Yes, you can. You can.
如果灭霸拿到宝石 半个宇宙都会消亡
If he gets the stone, half the universe dies.
这是很不公平
It's not fair.
这事情不应该由你来做 却必须是你
It shouldn't be you, but it is.
没关系的
It's all right.
你永远都不会伤害到我
You could never hurt me.
我只会感觉到你
I just feel you.
没事的
It's all right.
我爱你
I love you.
我理解 孩子
I understand, my child.
比任何人都理解
Better than anyone.
你永远都不会理解
You could never.
我今天所失去的超乎你的认知
Today, I lost more than you can know.
但现在不是哀悼的时候
But now is no time to mourn.
现在时间没有任何意义
Now is no time at all.
不！
No!
我告诉过你
I told you...
你会为此偿命的
you'd die for that.
你应该...
You should have...
你应...
You should...
你应该瞄准我的头
You should have gone for the head.
不！
No!
女儿？
Daughter?
你成功了吗？
Did you do it?
是的
Yes.
代价是什么?
What did it cost?
一切
Everything.
你做了什么？
What did you do?
What'd you do?
他去哪了？
Where'd he go?
索尔...
Thor.
他去哪了？
Where'd he go?
史蒂夫？
Steve?
起来 将军 快起来！
Up, General. Up!
现在不是倒下的时候
This is no place to die.
陛下
格鲁特对浣熊说的这句话 经银护导演詹姆斯古恩确认 含义为“父亲”
我是格鲁特...
I am Groot.
不
Oh...
不 不 别走！格鲁特....
No, no, no!
格鲁特 不...
Groot! No.
山姆
Sam!
山姆 你在哪？
Sam, where you at?
好像发生了什么事...
Something's happening.
奎尔
Quill?
冷静 奎尔 - 哦 天啊...
Steady, Quill. - Oh, man.
托尼
Tony.
没有别的办法了
There was no other way.
斯塔克先生
Mr. Stark?
我感觉不太好...
I don't feel so good.
你没事的 - 我不 我不知道是怎么回事
You're all right. I don't... I don't know what's happening.
我不知道
I don't know...
我不想走
I don't want to go.
我还不想走 斯塔克先生 求你
I don't want to go, sir. Please.
别 我还不想死  我还不想死
Please, I don't want to go. I don't want to go.
对不起
I'm sorry.
他得手了
He did it.
这是怎么回事？到底发生了什么？
What is this? What the hell is happening?
天啊
Oh, God.
还没有斯塔克的消息吗
Still no word from Stark?
还没有
No, not yet.
我已经动用了所有的卫星搜索斯塔克的下落
We're watching every satellite on both hemispheres, but still nothing.
那是什么？
What is it?
瓦坎达上空多个不明物体
Multiple bogeys over Wakanda.
跟纽约的能量特征是同一种吗？
Same energy signature as New York?
要大十倍
Ten times bigger.
通知克林特 我们约他在...
Tell Klein we'll meet him at...
尼克 尼克
Nick! Nick!
他们没事吧？
They okay?
车里没人
There's no one here.
通知指挥部
Call Control.
红色警戒
Code red.
尼克
Nick.
希尔
Hill.
不
Oh, no.
他妈...
Mother...
发送中...
惊奇队长的标志 《惊奇队长》定档2019年3月8日北美上映
灭霸将会回归